# James Loucks Fullstack developer

Vancouver, Canada 778-888-1496 james.loucks.codes@gmail.com

With a diverse history of 7+ years of experience, from serverless applications to dev-ops, and a background in 3D rendering. Proven technical leader; delivered project plans, managed timelines, and mentored new employees. Deep knowledge of security from the bare-metal to the application level, and of modern web frameworks.

# Technical Summary

Bash, Bootstrap, C, C#, C++, Cg, Css, Express, Groovy, Hibernate, Html, Java, Javascript, Jvm, Lua, Mssql, Mysql, Node, Php, Python, React, Redux, Swing, Typescript, Wordpress

# Professional History

# Software Developer

Speedline Solutions May 2017 - present

Small development team focused on launching a new platform for online-ordering that integrates with legacy in-store offering. Hired as experienced web developer for work on maintaining modern best-practices.

- Evangelising modern node is conventions that can apply to project
- Design and implement features for the online ordering system
- Collaborate with team leads for interface and architectural design
- Technical resource for Node, React, and web 2.0

mobile react redux typescript lambda webpack continuous integration travis-ci express node npm kanban windows bootstrap html css

# Software Developer

Boats Group Feb 2016 - May 2017

International company dealing with millions of users, providing global portals for posting boat sales. They have diverse technology stacks, but a flat heirarchy.

- Part of a global team that agile method to give weekly deliverables
- Designing and implementing highly-scalable next generation of internal APIs on NodeJs and Grails on top of MySQL and ElasticSearch and queues
- Lead several presentations to modernise and simplify the codebases
- Improved the onboarding process and guided new developers
- Technical lead for a top priority project
  - Responsible for design
  - Timeline estimation
  - Architectural decisions, after collaborating with several domain experts to learn the existing systems and dependencies
  - Communicated with the external client at the C-level
  - Carried it to completion on schedule

responsive mobile javascript rest api-gateway elastic groovy node npm agile linux java jvm bootstrap hibernate express html css

# System Analyst / Fullstack Developer

French School Board

November 2010 - February 2016

A small, diverse team focused on delivering all of the technical services and applications built specifically for francophone teachers in BC. We built fit-for-purpose applications to administer tests and track scores, custom integrations with larger software suites, and maintained learning software with updates and custom plugins.

- Design, implement, deploy, and maintain web applications
- Administer systems and provide security patching
- Manage cron jobs, and clone test-systems
- Lead training seminars for software we've rolled out into our organisation
- Wear many hats, filling any needs of the team; graphic design, audio recording, etc.
- Outside of assigned tasks
  - Encouraged adoption of newer programming conventions
  - Designing RESTful APIs
  - Use of modern web standards

All work was in French.

macOS redhat LAMP administration javascript python linux php java jvm swing tomcat apache mssql mysql html css

#### Web Consultant & Visual Artist

Red on Black Music (Volunteer)

Oct 2014 - Oct 2015

Reacting quickly to short deadlines and changing requirements; develop changes to the website (plug-in administration, graphics, etc.) using a Kanban-style todo list.

wordpress photoshop css php kanban illustration

# Education

# System Administrator II Certificate

Red Hat Certification May 2012

From RedHat: "An IT professional who has earned the Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA®) is able to perform the core system administration skills required in Red Hat Enterprise Linux environments."

- Complete knowledge of the Linux command-line environments
- Deploy, configure, and maintain systems
- Manage securiy, including firewall and SELinux

bash redhat selinux linux crontab

### Visual and Game Programming Diploma

Art Institute of Vancouver September 2010

Completion of the final project necessitated the command of modern programming paradigms, in-depth knowledge of asset pipelines and game engines (both Unreal and Unity).

- Team-based projects, SCM, Scrum, and Agile teams
- Implented design patterns and algorithms, such as search, and A\*
- Acquired deep understanding of C++, C#, cg, and Python
- Memory management techniques, pointer arithmetic
- Networking in real-time with UDP and TCP/IP
- Focus on 3d math; implemented and used quaternion, matrix, and vector operations
- Designed and implemented shaders for custom engine, and exporters for Maya

c++ c c# cg lua python scrum

#### **IB** Certificate

Port Moody Secondary SchoolJune 2007